Mama?
Well, your father always
picks you up, right?
Daikichi isn't my father.
My father is Grandpa.
That's weird!
Everyone has a mother and father.
So what's Daikichi?
I don't know...
What's that?!
Rin-chan always says strange stuff!
Men can't have babies!
Shut up!
You don't need a dad!
Dummies!
It takes one to know one.
Dummy, dummy, dummy!
Hiro-sensei!
Let's go!
Kouki-kun called me a dummy!
Kouki-kun kept saying dummy!
Hiro-sensei!
Kouki-kun, do you just
live with your mother?
My dad went off somewhere,
and then they got a divorce.
What's a "divorce"?
It's quitting marriage!
Maybe my mother is gone
because she got a divorce...
I dunno.
If you don't wear your hat,
they'll get mad at you.
What?
Your string is stretched out.
Rin-chan! You're getting picked up!
Rin-chan!
It's Daikichi!
He's here to pick you up!
Rintan, pibbup!
Maa-kun, it's okay!
Thank you.
See you tomorrow, Rin-chan.
Goodbye!
What do you feel like having for dinner?
Um, let's see...
Kouki-kun!
Your mother's here to pick you up!
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
Your mother's beautiful, you know?
At home, she's a noisy old woman!
U-Um...
Apparently, Rin always
looks after Kouki...
R-Really?
My son can be a little abrasive, so
he's had trouble making friends...
Thank you so much.
Oh, no! Not at all...
I-I should be thanking you...
My Rin is incredibly unsociable...
Maybe it's like birds of a
feather flock together, huh?
Daikichi! You were just talking
about me, weren't you?!
I wasn't saying anything bad.
Now walk fast.
I don't want you to demand that
I carry you half the way again...
I won't say that!
Let's go!
Is Rin-chan Daddy's girl?
Oh, I'm not her father.
I'm more like a relative, or...
I-I'm sorry, what was I thinking?!
N-Not at all!
Mom, you're too slow!
It's nice that you made a friend, huh?
Yep!
Kouki-san said he doesn't have a father.
He said his father went
somewhere after the divorce.
Rin... You know what divorce is?
Yeah. When marriage is finished, right?
Yeah, more or less...
If God finds out, He punishes
the people, doesn't he?
Mmm...
I wonder if my mom is gone
because of divorce, too...
Do you want to meet her?
I don't know.
I see.
But you know...
If she's like Kouki-kun's mother,
I think I want to meet her!
Me too! Me too!
What?!
Rin-chan's mother is...?!
Yeah. Grandpa's maid is
probably Rin's mother.
I don't believe it...
Have you heard anything about the maid?
Friday, January 25th, from 7pm
This was pretty cool.
A farewell party? For me?
I'm sorry it's taken so long.
Winter clothing orders have
finally settled down, so...
Thanks.
But I just can't go out at night.
My girl's six, see...
Are you telling me you haven't
gone out drinking once since...?
Yeah. I just can't get out.
And I don't even care about
drinking and that stuff anymore.
Maybe it's my age...
But you're only 30...
Anyway, the people in my
shipping department are young,
but a lot of them have kids.
So it isn't customary
to go out drinking...
Right?
You got that right.
I gotta pick up the kid
at nursery school, anyway.
We had two kids in two years and
the younger is 3 months old,
so if I don't get home quick, my wife...
Turns into "Wifezilla", right?
When she gets mad, she's
one scary monster...
Kawachi-kun!
Gotou-san!
I heard about the farewell party!
Yeah, but I can't go out at night, so...
But they went to the
trouble of arranging it,
so how about bringing the kid along?
I'll bring mine, too!
Is this your way of saying that you
want to go out drinking once in a while?
Anyway, anyway, it'll be fine!
I'm looking forward to it!
Coming, coming...
Daikichi, the phone.
Thanks.
Hello?
Daikichi? It seems Grandpa had a
regular maid, sent from an agency...
Whoa, whoa, wait a second...
So, do you know her name?
Yoshii Masako-san, spelled with the
kanji for "correct" and "child".
That's the name that's on the
mother-child health record book, isn't it?
I believe so...
Do you mean to contact her?!
She abandoned that precious child...
Calm down a little!
You saw the health record book, right?
There's a lot written in there...
There's still so much
we don't know, so...
Excuse me!
What I'm saying is...
I don't know the difference
anymore between work and home...
Pardon me for being late...
You're late! Here, have a seat!
Get away from me, you drunk!
Rin-chan?! You came?!
Thank you!
You're adorable!
Eat all you want!
Here you go.
I'm glad you're here, Rin-chan.
Thank you!
Here you are, Rin-chan.
Is orange juice okay?
Mm-hm!
Rin-chan is a beauty, isn't she?
Yep, she sure is a beauty!
She's embarrassed!
Yuu-kun, I'll gather
it together for you.
Rin-chan, thank you!
Kawachi-san, please, drink some more!
Rin might sleep on the way home, so...
Rin, I'm going to the washroom.
Say "bathroom"!
Yeah, yeah, I'm going to the bathroom.
He left our section high and dry.
It's like, don't produce
results, then bail!
Quitting while you're
ahead is playing dirty!
Sales has been tough this month...
Even if we do a decent job selling,
management won't look at anything
but last year's results!
What are we gonna do?
This is for the birds...
The old me would've stormed in and
read them the riot act, but...
I'm about to spring a leak...
Girls are so soft!
I wanna make you my kid!
What's really important
to me has changed.
Kawachi-san...
About your transfer...
After seeing Rin-chan, I've come around.
Yeah, right?!
Mama! Mama!
I want to hold her forever!
Pick me up, too!
Gotou-san, Rin-chan
doesn't wanna be held!
Masako-san...
What did you think about
your child... about Rin?
Yuu-kun was really cute, wasn't he?
You sure do love little kids, huh?
Yep! The mail came.
Thanks.
Says this is an elementary school
admission information session.
I didn't even do anything
and this came...
What's wrong?
There's an admissions test, isn't there?
No, no, no!
You can get in without taking any test!
Really?
For sure, for sure!
Compulsory education is amazing!
Drunk!
Shoot! How's this?!
Rin-chan, he's here!
P-Pardon me...
Tch! Everyone else already left!
So...rry...
Kouki-kun, your mother's here!
Sorry, Kouki...
H-Hello.
It's been... a while.
Daikichi, are we gonna make it in time?
I'll grab a taxi!
Sorry!
The childrens' name tags
can be turned around,
and they will be on the way home from
school, so their names aren't visible.
Another thing, tell your child not
to be alone at a park, for example,
and even if they see an adult that they
know, not to go off with that person.
It's tough, isn't it?
Instead of telling them to trust people,
we have to teach them to be suspicious.
Yeah...
That one sheet we were given...
Whoops...
I'll carry them! I've got them!
How do you know what vaccinations
were given up till now?
S-Sorry.
Seems like I just asked
an outlandish question...
Not at all...
Do you have Rin-chan's
health record book?
Yes, at home...
Mother-Child Health Record Book
It's got a vaccination record page.
So it's okay.
I see...
I really don't know anything...
See, I just met Rin for the
first time about 3 months ago...
Three months?
Yeah...
That's a surprise.
I got the feeling that Rin-chan trusts
in you implicitly, Daikichi-san...
I'm not sure about that...
At home, she talks back
a lot and she's a nag...
That's proof she trusts you.
It's obvious you're every bit a family.
Family...
R-Really?
That's right!
Maybe...
What?
I just jumped over your shadow!
I'm not tired!
That's okay.
Put me down!
Put me down, I said!
Thanks.
She's got almost everything on the list.
School satchel?
No, I haven't gotten that...
Well, you'd better!
By now, all the designer label and
fashionable ones are sold out!
A normal one is fine.
She's a girl, so that won't do!
Fine, I'll look this weekend.
Dai-chan, are you going
to really raise Rin-chan?
After all, you transferred
to another section, right?
I haven't really thought
ahead that far...
Mama!
Now I'll do your hair!
Okay!
You two are close, huh?
Mothers and daughters are like friends.
Come to think of it, Mom and
Kazumi are like buddies, too...
Who's to say that Masako-san's
situation hasn't changed
and now she wants to
live with her daughter?
Look at how many shots she's had...
Her mother must have...
Souichi's Will
Boing!
A will!
"Boing"?
"If Masako found it, she
would probably get rid of it.
Thus, I've taken this...
roundabout method.
However, I don't really know the proper
way to write a secret... riddle?
And this keyboard thing
is making a fool of me,
so I can't proceed at
but a snail's pace."
Even so, these kanji conversion
mistakes are dreadful!
"Already, this feeble-minded
old fool's energy is exhausted.
Therefore, I'm giving
up on this blog..."
That's giving up too soon!
What happened to the
"greatest generation"?!
"To be continued in Rin's mother-child
health record book..."
Sorry, Rin...
Let me have a look-see here...
Based on my prediction
that the person who found this piece
of paper thinks warmly of Rin,
I shall give an account here
of Rin and her mother, Masako.
Masako is easily misunderstood,
so I would like to start by saying
that she is by no means a bad girl.
She says that she's a
failure as a mother.
That she feels sorry for Rin.
Even now, she persists in being my maid.
And I believe that she
will continue to do so.
I think of that as Rin's
greatest happiness.
Happy? What's he mean?
She is living a vigilant life,
carefully leaving no traces of herself behind,
so that if something
should happen to me,
her existence will be hidden
from all of my relatives.
Masako certainly has a
mother's love for Rin.
But she's still young and may not yet
have the maturity to be a parent...
I don't really understand it...
But the one thing that's clear is
he cared about Rin and her mother.
Yoshii Masako
Daikichi!
W-What?!
Listen!
I want you to make my hair
look like rabbit ears!
Hah?
Like Reina-chan's mom did before!
I can't!
Do it!
There's no way I can do
it! It's out of my league!
Do it, I said!
'Cause...
she said I wasn't cute!
Huh?
Someone told you that?
Mii-chan said I wasn't cute at all!
Huh?
I think Rin wins hands down...
I wanna be cute, too...
All right, all right...
She's already grown to be a fine girl
and that means her feelings
can definitely be hurt...
Masako-san, did you know...?
Already, Rin's mind has developed a lot.
She's mature in some
ways, in others not.
That's why an adult has
to keep an eye on her.
Fin...ished!
This is...
Twinkle, twinkle, little star...
H-Hey, Rin...
How I wonder what you...
What are you doing?
It's a secret, so I can't tell
anyone at home about Parents' Day!
Hah? Parents' Day?
So you can't look!
S-She's gonna do it with that hairstyle?
Twinkle, twinkle, little star,
Yoshii Masako
How I wonder what you are.
If you left Rin alone,
thinking she'd eventually even forget
something painful like that...
Up above the world so high,
Like a diamond in the sky.
I have no scruples about hating you.
I want you to at least
have had a good reason,
Twinkle, twinkle, little star,
How I wonder what you are.
but what could be a good reason
for abandoning a child?
Study desk  Study chair
This is cute!
It's cute, but...
But you're going to be using it for a
long time, so we want something more...
Oh, I know!
A desk that looks like it's for a young
lady would be better, don't you think?
Young lady?
Yeah! One that's for
a young lady is good!
Yes!
You're sitting there again?
Do I look like a young lady?
Yeah. And I think you
could still use the desk
even when you're a high school student.
Is a high school student an adult?
I guess half an adult...
Listen to me read!
"A girl went alone
into a forest to play.
She lost her way and looked
for the path to get back home,
but she just couldn't find it.
Suddenly, before she knew it, there
was a tiny house in the forest."
Is this Yoshii-san?
Yes...
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
This is cute, isn't it?
Again?! Rin!
Rin!
Hey!
Daikichi...
I told you not to run off
on your own like that!
Okay...
What's that?
It can make me into a young lady!
Forget it!
This is for much later!
Why?